Nithin Teja Ganagani

Senior Data Scientist | Kroll | 1Digitals | Infosys

U₊₉₁₋₇₃₈₂₃₀₉₇₇₉

nitinteia.ganagani@gmail.com

Onitinaiet

in <u>Nithin Teja Ganagani</u>

Summary

Highly motivated and experienced Data Scientist with 7+ years of strong expertise in NLP for building AI Applications in Financial Services & e-Commerce domain. Good Team player with strong analytical and problem solving skills. Responsible & Accountable.

Work Experience

Senior Data Scientist, Kroll - formerly Duff & Phelps (May 2020 - Present)

Due Diligence Research System (An end-to-end AI Application)

- Developed an end-to-end AI based research application heavily focused on Query Understanding, Information Extraction,
 Retrieval, Ranking, Categorizing & Grouping using basic & advanced NLP techniques for multiple languages.
- Developed Entity Extraction engine using Spacy NER for Feature Extraction & Query Recommendation to expand the scope of research.
- Developed a Binary Classification model to assess the relevance of an article to the subject using classical ML models.
- Developed a Multi-class classification model using Hugging Face BERT model
- Developed a Name Variation Generator for USA & 4 other jurisdictions to enhance research capability of the Application.
- Integrated & Deployed all the above models into our Research System Pipeline to provide cumulative report on the Subject.
- Contributed for a couple of POCs on Gen AI using LLMs for Conversational AI & RAG.
- Collaborated with multiple teams (MLOps, AppDev, BA, Product Owners & EndUsers) in Application planning & development
- Strong Experience in working with DEV, QA, UAT & Prod environments as part of CI/CD.

Research Engineer AI | Conversational AI Developer, 1Digitals (Jan 2019 - March 2020)

Conversational AI, Recommendation Engine

- Developed an AI Assistant (Chatbot) for an e-Commerce Customer Support team which greatly reduced delays in Support.
- Developed an AI Shopping Assistant for quick Product Discovery & Checkout ability with a Product Recommendation Engine.
- Integrated a Defective Product Identification model into a chatbot which will classify the uploaded image into defective/non-defective and will immediately create a JIRA ticket to the Customer Support Team if it is defective.
- Built a POC for Entity Extraction for a Chatbot's NLP Engine.

Research Engineer AI, Skyris Technologies (Sept 2018 - Dec 2018)

NLP, Data Collection, Computer Vision

- Developed python scripts to automate the process of Data Collection from Wikipedia & other public sources through Web Scraping.
- Presented a POC Extractive Text Summarization using gensim.
- Developed a Facial Recognition based Attendance system using OpenCV.

Systems Engineer, Infosys Ltd (Jan 2017 - June 2018)

Data Visualization & Analysis

- Developed a dashboard for an e-Commerce client for regular analysis of their website's performance.
- Trained on Python & JEE for Backend development.

Skills & Technologies

- Machine Learning, Deep Learning, NLP, Gen Al, Conversational AI (Chatbots), Product Development
- Python, PyTorch, JEE, MySQL
- Azure, CI/CD, Docker, Git

Education

B. Tech, Sreenidhi Institute of Science & Technology, 2012-2016

Achievements

- Promoted twice in last 2 years for exceptional work in AI Application Development
- Secured 3rd position with 0.82 Accuracy Score in a Kaggle InClass competition in 2018 as part of a course by IIT-M Professors. A total of 1260 individuals participated in the ML Classification problem (Mobile Like-Unlike Classification)

Certifications

- Certified Microsoft Azure Data Science Associate (2021)
- Certified Applied Data Scientist by MUST Research (2020)
- PadhAl Deep Learning (2019)
- IIIT Hyderabad Advanced Certification in Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning (2018)
- Udemy- Machine Learning A-Z[™]: Hands-On Python & R in Data Science (2018)